I'm really excited to continue our series, although we're just entitled All In.
At the beginning of the year, we've been taking individual kind of aspects and areas of our
life and asking the question, am I all in with this area of my life when it comes to
my relationship with Jesus? And I don't know about you, but it's been both challenging
and encouraging for me. So far, we've talked about our learning, our body, and many of the
I don't want to talk about my soul this week, but it was so good for me. Thank you, man.
So in the next few weeks, I'm going to be talking about our relationships. Yes, that's right.
Me this week and next week. So for 10 minutes as well next week, I know it's because I warned
you what was going to be me. So no, you have to talk, just so that I'm not insecure about
my freaky abilities, okay? But here's what we're going to be talking about relationships.
If you were in a marital flight in the car on the way here, if maybe you're in a dating relationship
where you maybe shouldn't be, or you're single and you don't want to be single, take a deep
breath. That's not the kind of relationships we're talking about. So don't worry about it.
We might get to those another time. But this week, we're going to talk about our Christian
relationships, the community that Matt talked about when it comes to us coming together.
It takes a village, right? To raise children, to do life, to bring the kingdom of God to our
city. It takes Christian community. And next week, we're going to talk about our friends that
don't know Jesus and what we might be able to do to help introduce them to the Savior that
has transformed our lives. Sound like a good plan? Cool. Let's pray and then we'll get
to it. Father, I thank you so much for a different opportunity to stand together with the Spirit.
God, I'm thankful for the people that are in the room that aren't really sure where they're
out with you, that they can experience what it means to really work with you. God, I'm thankful
for your word. So obviously, we have to look deeply at it this morning. I pray that you would
not allow us to be comfortable in our isolation. God, that we will be caught out of loneliness
and isolation into community even when it's difficult. And even when people have broke our
hearts, sinned against us and hurt us, may we still be reminded of your word that that community
is worshiped, that you've called us to it, and that we should be active, participating in it.
In Jesus' name, I pray. Amen. Let me be honest this morning, not that I'm usually meant, but
in the transparency, this is an extremely difficult message for me to write this week. I stared at a
blank sheet of paper much longer than I normally stare at a blank sheet of paper. I was struggling
so bad. At one point, I purchased this online teaching class that I've been learning to take
for a while, and this time I got around to this. It was so bad, I was like, I'm going to watch a
couple videos of this preaching class, and maybe, just maybe it'll give me something. Maybe I'll
come out of the room and feel like I know how to preach again. And I just, I just struggled
with it. And the reason I struggled with it is because historically, myself and my pastor's
friends, I think, and I know I have, have spoken about Christian community in kind of some cheap,
free stay-a-ways. We have these cheap phrases, and it's awesome. We preach this message when we're
launching small groups. We're trying to convince people to find them for small groups, and it's
going to be great. It's going to change your life, and you can be the same that we want you to do.
Anybody ever sat through one of those?
I've preached them before. I really have. I've done it. And I didn't want to do that. One reason
I didn't want to do this is because we don't have enough time for everybody to do this. We've
only got to fix markets, and like most of them are four already, which is a title. We'll fix that
eventually. But meanwhile, I just wanted to avoid Christians. I didn't want to overcome this
in the underworld. I don't know about you, but my reality when it comes to Christian community
has been filled with some of the best experiences of my life and some of the absolute worst experiences
of my life. And how can I acknowledge that tension this morning while still preaching to both you
and me what I believe to be true in God's Word that it's worth it, that Christian community is what
we're called to while still acknowledging that it really often falls short of what we hope that it
will be. And so I wanted to start by just telling you a couple stories of some friends of mine and
their experience of community, Christian community, and my own experience of Christian community to
try and build that tension as we lead into what I hope will be following us out of our contentment
and isolation into Christian community. I had a friend in place of England and Steph, and it's by
God's name, and it's by God's grace that we became friends, our church in Texas only had two services,
a 9 o'clock and 11 o'clock. And in one week, we decided we were going to change and we were going to go to
one 10 a.m. service. We were going to have him past the house. It was going to be great. It was going to be
awesome. Our mom's spouse didn't get the memo. And so he did what he has done for most of his life, which was
so I was just sitting by himself when he stopped 20 minutes late. He literally had a time to like when the
last song was about to wrap up, he would come in and he would listen to the message and then he would
leave during the last song. This was such a pattern of behavior. And unfortunately for him, he missed the
memo that we switched to a 10 a.m. service. So he showed up for 10 a.m. service at 9:20 and he was just sitting by
himself in the middle of the queue. And that's like, that's like pastor like camp, right? I'm just like,
there's a guy here 40 minutes early by himself. I'm going to talk to him. And so thankfully through
that one accidental encounter, I was able to kind of call space out on this idea that he had. And this
idea that he had in most of his Christian lives was following Jesus as an individual friend. It's
between me and Jesus. I don't need anybody else for me and Jesus to have a relationship.
He said, "This was self-expective and he's from a freeing and from annoying him." He started
when he decided to come to a small victim. And over the years, he ended up becoming something
special of all of our entire community. And he was the guy that everyone was tonight to.
Well, my friend Billy, Billy was a little different from a lot of other people. And he just never
felt like he fit in. He tried to teach as a church, a few churches. He just couldn't find
the place where he's given me. And my own experience and maybe one of your experiences
where I've been in violent Christian community and then I've been in Christian community where the
people that I love the most let me down the heart.
Last one, my friend Rob, who reluctantly came to a small group telling me that he has always found
better and deeper and meaningful community at the local bar than I could preach.
And my guess is that most of us can resonate with at least one of these Christians. Most of us have
experienced at least one of these situations when it comes to our kids. And you're even,
even if you're godlier than me, and you aren't yet dated around this idea of Christian community.
We live in a culture where it's really so easy to become isolated. Think about it. Do you work from
home? Do you start from home? Do you, anybody that eats from home? Do you go to,
do you go to, do you go to a doctor from home? I did that the other day. I went to a doctor from
home. That's crazy. You go to a doctor from home. Do you work out from home? And sometimes you even
go to church from home and all of my introverts said, "Hey, the same." Right? But it's not extremely
intentional in our cultural moment. It would be very easy for us to flip into a pattern of isolation
and loneliness. And somehow we're still crazy busy. How's that possible? Totally lonely and isolated and
busy at the same time. This is the cultural moment that we find ourselves in. I heard one psychologist
put it this way. He said, "People are doing," and I think that's a little accusatory if I do say so
myself. So I'm going to stop for a minute. Let me say it's unintentionally falling into. He says we're
doing it on purpose. I say it's an accident. I'm only doing an optimist. "People are unintentionally
falling into a place that destroys their mental health and robs them of real joy and lasting fulfillment."
Seems like we have a lot working against us when it comes to a violent, healthy expression of community.
We've got bad experiences, busy schedules, an isolated culture, not to mention an enemy of God that prowls
around like a roaring lion seeking to destroy you. And I don't know if you watched National Geographic
videos of lion hunting, but they don't go after the pets. They go after the isolated animals.
And so if the enemy can isolate us from our Christian community,
he can destroy us. And with all of that as our bed sucks, very depressing, I know,
we find ourselves tuning into an hour-long service that we call church, which is really problematic. Because the word
church has nothing to do with an hour-long service or a good thing to walk into two to three times a month for love to.
The word "church" means an assembly, a group, a community of called out people. 1 Peter says that you,
Christians, are a chosen people. Not a chosen person, a chosen people. A royal priesthood, a holy nation, a group of,
people of, a community of people for God's own possession. The very thing we are doing was never
intended to be a service to a change, content to consume, or a building to inhabit, but a community of
people to engage in. I've never envisioned an isolated group of people that gather together in a room for an hour once a twice a week.
And so often that's what we settle for. We're like what C.S. Lewis calls, and we've heard this quote,
ignorant children who want to go on making mud pies in the throne because we cannot imagine what is made by the
of a case of abuse. We are far too easily pleased. Jesus is calling us out of isolation and loneliness into this
authentic, visible expression of community. And we say no to it because we're content with this individual,
personal relationship. It's meaning God, and I'll handle everything else on my own.
That's fine for me and for you is that we would form a vibrant and authentic community that would
exemplify the way of Jesus to our community around us. I'll summarize it in this statement. I would say that
"Authentic biblical community is God's vehicle for holistic human authority." Wow, that's a pretty
powerful statement, right? I just spent the last 10 minutes complaining about Christian community,
and now I'm supposed to convince you that it's God's vehicle for holistic human authority. That
sounds like over-promising and under-deliverment, right? Anybody? Well, here's the fun thing about
preachings. That sometimes I'm both convincing myself and you at the same time of something the
Scripture says, even when I'm not so sure. It might be a fair critique for you to say, "Man, this
seems like a pretty powerful statement for a pretty big promise for biblical community." When your
first piece of experience and my experience doesn't always lose up to that, and that's just clear
critique. I'd respond to that critique with the story. When I went to Bible college, I was assigned
a remnant, but I had never met before. His name was Rob. He was great. Him and I were, which you
expect from freshmen, boys in college, irresponsible, slabs, late, all of the things, right? And him and I
used to ride the breakfast together. And the college that I went to, not many have vehicles. And Rob,
I just still happened to be blessed by God as a remnant of a vehicle. And so I was like, this works,
right? And so Rob and I would ride the breakfast together, but I can't tell you these things that I
remember. I was waking up at the very last second and running in the dorm room with maybe clothes and
put a little bit of a dress code because we were lucky. And getting ready to hop into his car to drive to
breakfast only to find him in his car because I went to school in northeast Pennsylvania was covered in
the front. So we did what any big college students could do. Roll up in those windows, start up the
car, and I would pick my head out the window and tell him how to navigate to the breakfast. That's a
that's a killer. I'm telling you this story because that situation, that vehicle that I had to get
to dress code might not have been the vehicle of choice, but it's the one we have. And you might
look at God's point, and God tells us, I believe in his word that the biblical community really is
the vehicle that he's going to use for our own flourishing and for the flourishing of those around us.
You might look at that and say, that's not how I would do it. I might look at that and say, I don't
know if that's how I would have designed it, but it is the vehicle that God gave us. And so for us to
neglect it would be forward. God has always been in the business of using broken people to display his plans of
salvation in broken but beautiful ways. His prayers before he went to the cross, in John chapter 17,
when he says this, I'm praying not only for my disciples, these disciples that are with me surrounding
me as I'm going to the cross, but also for anyone who will ever believe in me through their message.
As us, as Christians, followers of Jesus, we've made Jesus' prayers for you, and what is he praying
for you? I pray that they will be one, just as you and I are one, as you are in me, Father, and I am in you,
may they be in us, so that the world will believe that you sent me.
Jesus, he said, "It's better than I go so that the Holy Spirit will fill individual believers,
and then he prays that those individual believers won't stay individual, but they will gather
together as one group of people, and that through their unity and their love for one another,
the rest of the world will see what true Christian community looks like." This is Christ's prayer,
that the spirit of God would fill the people of God, and the people of God would form an authentic
community that could display his love and grace to a watching world. So, what does this look like?
What is an authentic biblical community that is God's vehicle for holistic humans for us to look
like? That's fantastic. First, with authentic, right? The community that Christ has called us in,
two is one, that we are willing to have all cards on the table. It's a community that values both
humility and honesty, refuses hypocrisy. First John, chapter one, verse eight, John says that if we claim,
we have no sin, we have no sin. We are only fooling ourselves and not living in truth.
When we see authentic community break down, it's when you and I think we're better than we have sin.
It's when you and I are telling them that we don't have sin, like we're in church,
So, let's be honest, most of us wouldn't say I'm honest enough. Right? Most of us wouldn't say that.
But, by our actions and what we think we play in our heads, oftentimes we think that we're better than we have sin.
We claim that we're not really that sinful. Or we look at other people and they're more sinful
than we are. And so, we create this kind of hypocritical, non-authentic, non-honest, non-humble
community because we're fooling ourselves and thinking that we're better than we actually are.
Our authenticity breaks down when we pretend that we're better than we really are. Or we justify our sin
because it doesn't seem like that we do. Sin will grow in your hearts. If you're not honest with
yourself and your brothers and sisters in Jesus, if you refuse to acknowledge or confess to be able
where you're selfish, where you're struggling, sin will grow. And where sin grows, destruction is
not far ahead. I'm just finding that a thing is like thunder growing under a dead tree stump.
It's dark. Nobody sees it, but it is growing like crazy.
I'm not, like, I'm not the prophetic that I was going to tell you what's true about you,
but for some reason it's not like the Lord. I'm just going to say this this week.
And I think some of us, we're weeks or months away from blowing up our lives because we're
not going out of things. Because we're fighting something deep down in our hearts.
It's probably not all of us, probably some of us, and it's probably, if it's you, you probably
know it. Because wrestle with God on that topic. Stop pretending like you're better than you are.
You're forming yourself. And there's grace and forgiveness in Jesus. This isn't, this isn't a
message that's changing. This is what the whole, the holistic community is all about, that you should
come to your friends, your brothers and sisters in Christ that you've touched and said, "I have
been messing up in a long time, and nobody knows, and I need help." And there's
forgiveness, and there's grace, and there's freedom, and he's sending a light on sin.
Jesus came to send a light on sin so that we could be free from it, delivered from it.
We're going to fight to build relationships with other followers of Jesus on the
foundation of grace and truth.
And speak honest with our brothers and sisters about what we're struggling with.
And if maybe you're like, so far away from blowing up your life that you know, like,
speak honest, confess our sins to another, one to another, and encourage one another,
dare you, so that none of us will be hardened by the lies that we're in it.
And if we're going to create an authentic fortune, not only do you have to confess our sins, but
if someone confesses our sins to you, you have to receive the grace and forgiveness.
That's not trying to make us a confession.
It's difficult, because one day you're going to be the one confessing the sin, and you want
to be received in grace and forgiveness.
So we're going to create a community that God uses to bring up a holistic
community that has to be authentic.
And I don't know about you, but I have a vision for our church to cultivate an authentic
community where we're filled with humility and we refuse hypocrisy.
And it starts with each of us.
It starts with you and me being honest about our brokenness, spreading grace and forgiveness
to those who are broken.
And this won't be easy, but it will be worth it.
So it works hard to build this kind of community.
We've got visions for our community, that's not just authentic, but it's also biblical.
Is it a triggering word for anyone in other cultures today?
The word biblical has kind of become a triggering word for a lot of people, a lot of my friends, a lot of people my age.
And I understand where they're coming from because many bad people have weaponized Scripture.
The Bible gets a bad name because of what bad people use it for.
But Jesus can't be the community that receives different places where it's through this place.
So we've got to be both authentic where our soul has to be biblical and has to be rooted in truth.
And what does that mean?
What does biblical community look like?
It might not exactly mean what you think it means.
See, sometimes when we think about biblical community, we think about it, right?
Everyone wants to send them to talk things the same way.
Because the Bible says so, right?
And so we all believe the exact same thing about everything.
The biblical community, throughout the Scriptures, is an extremely diverse community.
So, speaking of chapter 12, Paul says the human body has many parts, but the many parts make up one whole body.
So it is just the body of Christ.
Some of us are Jews.
Some of us are Gentiles.
Some of us are slaves.
Some of us are free relations.
Also, some of us are male and female, right?
But we have all been baptized into one spirit, into one body.
We all are spirit of the same spirit.
Biblical community is diverse.
And now, the conference of popular belief, Christian community shouldn't be an echo chamber of your own ideology.
I stole that phrase from somebody, and that is good.
And you kind of preach the better than you're responding.
Let me say this.
Christian community shouldn't be an echo chamber of your own ideology.
The gospel of Jesus has always been filled with people from different ethnicities, cultures, and ideologies.
The message of Jesus actually flips the cultural power structure upside down.
And if your Christian friendships are filled with people that look exactly like you, think exactly like you, talk exactly like you, believe 100% of the things that you believe, maybe it's not as biblical as you think it is.
This, again, if I think it's biblical to me is God's equal for holistic human flesh and into the blessing world, like if Jesus is going to take a community of people, and they're going to take the message of Jesus to the world, and they're going to see us in the way that we interact with one another.
I don't think there's going to be anything compelling to our neighbors if we all just look and exhibit their lives.
Oh, I don't think there's going to be anything compelling to our neighbors if we all just look and exhibit their lives.
The biblical community is by the list.
Our culture is full of communities of people that all agree.
They all have one mind and one idea, one thing that they believe in.
And that, or they refuse to talk about the things that they disagree on.
But this means that the same spirit will pledge allegiance to the same Savior, which means we should be able to have community and conversations about things that we don't necessarily agree on.
We should have an unexplainable unity in the midst of difficult disagreements.
This is what Jesus prayed for.
That people would know that you're my disciples, by the way, that you love one another.
To be honest, I'm going to learn the right stuff.
I don't know why I have those questions.
I shouldn't do that.
Maybe that's in my preaching class.
I have a video from them.
I know you're all learning better.
Being corrupted isn't funny.
No one likes confrontation in a moment, but some of my deepest moments of spiritual growth has happened when a brother or sister that I love us pulled me aside and looked me in the face and corrected me with truth.
Good will for the truth.
I don't know why I love you, but I have a reason for a diverse community of people from different backgrounds and cultures with different ideas, all finding common unity around the empty tomb of Jesus.
My hope is that this all sounds really good to me, but how do we get there?
Here's the bad news.
Come on, I'm going to show the Lord.
I think this biblical community is fertile and difficult and hard.
And it takes intention and hardy and commitment.
It requires us to intentionally get out of roads and into circles.
The authentic biblical community never is going to come from a few hours on a Sunday with 200 people in the room.
I think this community will be, not just be built on Sunday mornings, but in living rooms, community parks, hiking trails, vineyards, cigar shops, anywhere else you live, work, worship, or play.
Let's get in relationships with one another outside of the larger congregation.
Hebrews chapter 10, again, intention and hardy and commitment.
The writer of Hebrews says, let us hold tightly without a wavelength of hope we affirm.
It's biblical.
We all have the same thing.
We all have the same message of salvation.
We all tightly present so that you can be trustful.
But let us think of ways to motivate one another to act of love and good work.
Ooh, we're not so positive biblical truth.
We don't just get to fill our minds with it.
We don't just all of you have the same ideas, but we actually have to go live it out.
And you say, how does this happen?
Let us not neglect our meeting together.
As some people do, it's going to be tempting to just take your relationship without sliding here,
sit in a room, celebrate with a bunch of people, and then get out of here
when you don't ever have a real conversation with anybody.
Don't neglect your meeting together, as some people do.
Encourage one another, especially not if the day we saw in New York.
Hebrews 3 says, encourage one another, really.
Build relationships with both your sisters in Christ.
We'll see you on a regular basis during the week, and know when things aren't going well.
You can be there for me.
These kinds of things are filled with intentionality.
When we live in a culture, I think it is always a reality, but our culture is, it's just sinful, right?
Like, our culture is directed by many ideas that are always going to be.
We live in a culture that pushes compatibility over commitment.
Our communities, we're encouraged to get in communities with people that we're compatible with,
rather than being committed to the group of people that God has called us to.
It took me like, I'm working on my life, because I love his life.
It took me like six days in my life to realize that I'm not compatible with anyone.
I'm a sinner, man.
I am a jerk, and I constantly do things to hurt the person that I love the most.
And people that love me constantly do things to hurt me.
We're not compatible with each other.
And that's why, if we're going to have an authentic biblical community, we have to be committed to it.
And this verse that we read all the time in our wedding, from St. James 13, about what love is.
And when we read it, we said, we're trying to encourage that couple, look, in like three days,
you're not going to love each other very much.
And it takes a vow.
It takes a commitment.
It takes intentionality.
The supremacy verse isn't written to married couples.
It's written to others.
This is what Paul says to be free of our community.
We should be committed in unconditional love that is patient and cunning,
not jealous or boastful or proud or rude.
Some of us are really biblical and really rude.
Not irritable.
Keeps no record of being alone.
Doesn't rejoice about injustice, but rejoices whenever truth brings up.
Love never gives up.
Commitment.
Love never loses faith.
Always hopeful when he endures through every circumstance.
I don't know about you, but I have a vision for a group of people that are authentic,
averse, and committed to one another because of our individual commitment to Jesus.
I don't know about you, but this sounds like something that's worth repending and difficulty.
There is hope that it's formed.
And this community that we've discussed for the last few months, I believe, is God's vehicle for holistic human policing.
And I realize that that is a very loaded thing.
It's my attempt to paraphrase Christ's invitation in John chapter 10, that he came to give life and life more abundantly.
Abundantly, the invitation to follow Jesus, it is sacrificial, it does mean laying down our lives.
But the promise is that we will receive a life that is far more abundant than the one we would have had if we follow our own desires for the rest of our lives.
Community is the vehicle that God uses to bring us to the vision that he has for our lives, to be holistic, to be spiritual, physical, emotional, mental, to be all of these areas of our lives.
We get a picture of what this looked like in early church in Acts chapter 2 most of the years.
In other words, this comes as we actually read it, not too long ago, it's a goal months ago.
Acts chapter 2, Acts chapter 2, Acts chapter 42, this is the first church gathering together.
There's three thousands of them that are ahead of the church.
And it says there's all the believers devoted themselves to the apostles' teaching, to fellowship, to share meals, including the Lord's Supper, and to serve.
A deep sense of awe came over all of them.
And the apostles performed many miraculous signs and wonders.
It's a spiritual component to this community.
They worship together.
They play together.
They saw God do incredible things through their community.
It's a deep sense of love.
It wasn't just spiritual, though.
It wasn't just, let's come, worship together, and then move on.
It was physical.
It says, all the believers met together in one place and shared everything that they had.
There was this contagious generosity about them.
They sold their property and possessions, and they shared their money with those in need.
It's physical, but it's spiritual.
They worshiped together at the temple each day.
This is where it's really uncomfortable for Americans.
They met from their homes.
I don't know if somebody had a brother or sister in Christ in a living room.
It's strange.
We don't do it very much anymore.
It's weird.
You know what?
I think the community had happened.
Didn't it say that it's really nice?
It was a spiritual worship and a physical care for one another, which led to, I believe, emotional and mental health.
It says, with great joy and generosity, all the while praising God and enjoying the good will of all people.
That sounds like a holistic human person.
And what happened when they took care of one another.
What happened when they formed this authentic biblical community where a holistic human person was helping in their grief.
Each day, the Lord added to those fellowships, those who were being saved, because their neighbors, their co-workers, their friends,
they saw the community that was being formed around the gospel of Jesus, and they said,
What's going on?
I want thanks.
I want to be able to fail and have to fail.
And receive forgiveness and grace and unconditional love.
I want to have the worst day of my life and somebody that I'm all ready to fill up and hold up my arms because I can't hold them up on my own.
This is the type of community that God says is going to bring about holistic human person,
the abundant life for us and for those around me.
Seek the children.
The thing on what can't you expect, like 61 out of this name.
You can't do those things on your own.
Therefore, they love one another.
So if I should tell everybody to one another, encourage one another, care for one another,
I'll do one another in filling on you.
I think it's biblical community.
And it's not biblical.
It might not be the one you would choose.
Introverts in the room, I know.
But is there another way?
No, there isn't.
But it isn't.
This is it.
It's the thing that you need to pray for.
And it's the thing that's going to bring about the kingdom of God and the city of Uncensored as it is in heaven.
It's us in the intentional, the form of authentic, biblical community.
We can't do it alone.
Eugene Peterson is one of my favorite Christian words.
He says it this way.
He says there can be no maturity in the spiritual life, no obedience in following Jesus, no fullness in the Christian life, apart from the immersion in and embrace of community.
And I love this one.
And he says, I'm not going to run myself.
I'm not going to do it.
I'm going to do it.
I'm a one-on-one user.
I love users, but don't like to speak with it.
I get it.
It might not be the thing for you to choose,
but it's the one that I'm going to do is I think,
but we've got to be intentional calling it into it.
We've got those in the first community
by people that have listening ability who didn't really
certainly need anywhere else to sit in here,
to belong to our community, to stay.
And it sounds really good at the end of the message,
but you guys know what that means, right?
It might be weird because God likes to save weird people.
And I want the communities around to say,
"You're too weird for this community.
You've got too much stuff going on.
You've got too many different ideas for them."
You love Jesus?
You love him.
You've got a vision for that sort of community.
It's like a community where people like me,
and I know so many of you,
would be convinced that it's worth forgiving
and forgiving opinions.
It's worth forgiving people that you don't want to give.
It's worth filling up day in and day out.
It's not got a vision for a community that's compelling
to keep a lot like my friend around.
It might be convinced that Christian community is not a city critical
or the beauty of the way, and that he would realize that there is a far greater community here
than that's what I would want.
So this is the type of authentic community that starts with you and his need being intentional
as one of those.
And I'm crazy enough to believe that if he did it right, that God is going to be in for Christ's
for and God's everything, and that our neighbors, and our co-workers, and our friends,
and we know that Jesus is God.
He took a lot of love for him.
Amen.
That's our growth plan here, it's kind of community situation.
That's how the kingdom of God comes to the city of Winchester.
I've been committed and intentionally to form authentic biblical community.
That's proud.
God, I thank you for your words that often changes me to do things that I don't want to do.
Often calls me the places that I don't want to go.
Often encourages me to do life with people that I'm not so sure about.
God, but I trust you.
I trust your work.
May we be a people that trust your words, and may we be a people that is authentic,
and even if it was the one we wouldn't see.
May we be invested in it, and may you reach lots of people all over the city because of the
way that we live and love it.
May you stay in my faith.
Amen.